<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="full">Ten days that shook the World/Appendices</title>
            <title type="full">APPENDIX TO CHAPTER X</title>
            <author cert="high">John Reed</author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Texte encodé dans le cadre du devoir GIT de l'ENC</resp>
               <name>Julien Fenech</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
            <publisher ref="contributor">Internet Archive</publisher>
            <pubPlace>New York, New York, United States of America</pubPlace>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ten Days That Shook the World by John Reed</title>
               <distributor
                  facs="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Ten_Days_That_Shook_the_World/Appendices"/>
               <biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="420">pp.325-420</biblScope>
            </bibl>
            <biblStruct>
               <monogr>
                  <imprint>
                     <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
                  </imprint>
               </monogr>
            </biblStruct>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </creation>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textDesc n="novel">
            <channel mode="w">printed</channel>
            <constitution type="single"/>
            <derivation type="original"/>
            <domain type="art"/>
            <factuality type="mixed"/>
            <interaction type="none"/>
            <preparedness type="prepared"/>
            <purpose type="entertain" degree="high"/>
            <purpose type="inform" degree="high"/>
         </textDesc>
         <settingDesc>
            <setting>
               <name>Russia</name>
               <time>October 1917</time>
            </setting>
         </settingDesc>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head>APPENDIX TO CHAPTER X</head>
         <div type="numeric" n="1">
            <head>DAMAGE TO THE KREMLIN</head>
            <p>I myself verified the damage to the Kremlin, which I visited immediately after the
               bombardment. The Little Nicolai Palace, a building of no particular importance, which
               was occupied occasionally by receptions of one of the Grand Duchesses, had served as
               barracks for the yunkers. It was not only bombarded, but pretty well sacked;
               fortunately there was nothing in it of particular historical value.</p>
            <p>Usspensky Cathedral had a shell-hole in one of the cupolas, but except for a few feet
               of mosaic in the ceiling, was undamaged. The frescoes on the porch of
               Blagovestchensky Cathedral were badly damaged by a shell. Another shell hit the
               corner of Ivan Veliki. Tchudovsky Monastery was hit about thirty times, but only one
               shell went through a window into the interior, the others breaking the brick
               window-moulding and the roof cornices. </p>
            <p>The clock over the Spasskaya Gate was smashed. Troitsky Gate was battered, but easily
               reparable. One of the lower towers had lost its brick spire.</p>
            <p>The church of St. Basil was untouched, as was the great Imperial Palace, with all the
               treasures of Moscow and Petrograd in its cellar, and the crown jewels in the
               Treasury. These places were not even entered.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="numeric" n="2">
            <head>LUNATCHARSKY’s DECLARATION</head>
            <p>“Comrades! You are the young masters of the country, and although now you have much
               to do and think about, you must know how to defend your artistic and scientific
               treasures. </p>
            <p>“Comrades! That which is happening at Moscow is a horrible, irreparable misfortune….
               The People in its struggle for the power has mutilated our glorious capital.</p>
            <p>“It is particularly terrible in these days of violent struggle, of destructive
               warfare, to be Commissar of Public Education. Only the hope of the victory of
               Socialism, the source of a new and superior culture, brings me comfort. On me weighs
               the responsibility of protecting the artistic wealth of the people…. Not being able
               to remain at my post, where I had no influence, I resigned. My comrades, the other
               Commissars, considered this resignation inadmissible. I shall therefore remain at my
               post…. And moreover, I understand that the damage done to the Kremlin is not as
               serious as has been reported…. </p>
            <p>“But I beg you, comrades, to give me your support…. Preserve for yourselves and your
               descendants the beauty of our land; be the guardians of the property of the
               People.</p>
            <p>“Soon, very soon, even the most ignorant, who have been held in ignorance so long,
               will awake and understand what a source of joy, strength and wisdom is art….” </p>
         </div>
         <div type="numeric" n="3">
            <head>QUESTIONNAIRE FOR THE BOURGEOISIE</head>
            <p>[Graphic page-354]</p>
         </div>
         <div type="numeric" n="4">
            <head>REVOLUTIONARY FINANCIAL MEASURE: <hi rend="italic">Order</hi></head>
            <p>In virtue of the powers vested in me by the Military Revolutionary Committee attached
               to the Moscow Soviet of Workers’ and Soldiers’ Deputies, I decree:</p>
            <list rend="numbered">
               <item n="1">All banks with branches, the Central State Savings Bank with branches,
                  and the savings banks at the Post and Telegraph offices are to be opened beginning
                  November 22nd, from 11 A. M. to 1 P. M. until further order.</item>
               <item n="2">On current accounts and on the books of the savings banks, payments will
                  be made by the above mentioned institutions, of not more than 150 rubles for each
                  depositor during the course of the next week.</item>
               <item n="3">Payments of amounts exceeding 150 rubles a week on current accounts and
                  savings banks books, also payments on other accounts of all kinds will be allowed
                  during the next three days—November 22nd, 23d, and 24th, only in the following cases:<list>
                     <item n="(a)">On the accounts of military organisations for the satisfaction of
                        their needs; </item>
                     <item n="(b)">For the payment of salaries of employees and the earnings of
                        workers according to the tables and lists certified by the Factory
                        Committees or Soviets of Employees, and attested by the signatures of the
                        Commissars, or the representatives of the Military Revolutionary Committee,
                        and the district Military Revolutionary Committees.</item>
                  </list></item>
               <item n="4">Not more than 150 rubles are to be paid against drafts; the remaining
                  sums are to be entered on current account, payments on which are to be made in the
                  order established by the present decree. </item>
               <item n="5">All other banking operations are prohibited during these three
                  days.</item>
               <item n="6">The receipt of money on all accounts is allowed for any amount. </item>
               <item n="7">The representatives of the Finance Council for the certification of the
                  authorisations indicated in clause 3 will hold their office in the building of the
                  Stock Exchange, Ilyinka Street, from 10 A. M. to 2 P. M. </item>
               <item n="8">The Banks and Savings Banks shall send the totals of daily cash
                  operations by 5 P. M. to the headquarters of the Soviet, Skobeliev Square, to the
                  Military Revolutionary Committee, for the Finance Council. </item>
               <item n="9">All employees and managers of credit institutions of all kinds who refuse
                  to comply with this decree shall be responsible as enemies of the Revolution and
                  of the mass of the population, before the Revolutionary Tribunals. Their names
                  shall be published for general information. </item>
               <item n="10">For the control of the operations of Branches of the Savings Banks and
                  Banks within the limits of this decree, the district Military Revolutionary
                  Committees shall elect three representatives and appoint their place of business.
               </item>
            </list>
            <signed><hi rend="italic">Fully-authorised Commissar of the Military Revolutionary
                  Committee,</hi>
               <name>S. SHEVERDIN-MAKSIMENKO.</name></signed>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
