<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="full">Ten days that shook the World/Appendices</title>
            <title type="full">APPENDIX TO CHAPTER XII</title>
            <author cert="high">John Reed</author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Texte encodé dans le cadre du devoir GIT de l'ENC</resp>
               <name>Julien Fenech</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
            <publisher ref="contributor">Internet Archive</publisher>
            <pubPlace>New York, New York, United States of America</pubPlace>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ten Days That Shook the World by John Reed</title>
               <distributor
                  facs="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Ten_Days_That_Shook_the_World/Appendices"/>
               <biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="420">pp.325-420</biblScope>
            </bibl>
            <biblStruct>
               <monogr>
                  <imprint>
                     <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
                  </imprint>
               </monogr>
            </biblStruct>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </creation>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textDesc n="novel">
            <channel mode="w">printed</channel>
            <constitution type="single"/>
            <derivation type="original"/>
            <domain type="art"/>
            <factuality type="mixed"/>
            <interaction type="none"/>
            <preparedness type="prepared"/>
            <purpose type="entertain" degree="high"/>
            <purpose type="inform" degree="high"/>
         </textDesc>
         <settingDesc>
            <setting>
               <name>Russia</name>
               <time>October 1917</time>
            </setting>
         </settingDesc>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head>APPENDIX TO CHAPTER XII</head>
         <div type="numeric" n="1">
            <head>INSTRUCTION TO PEASANTS</head>
            <p>In answer to the numerous enquiries coming from peasants, it is hereby explained that
               the whole power in the country is from now on held by the Soviets of the Workers’,
               Soldiers’, and Peasants’ Deputies. The Workers’ Revolution, after having conquered in
               Petrograd and in Moscow, is now conquering in all other centres of Russia. The
               Workers’ and Peasants’ Government safeguards the interests of the masses of
               peasantry, the poorest of them; it is with the majority of peasants and workers
               against the landowners, and against the capitalists.</p>
            <p>Hence the Soviets of Peasants’ Deputies, and before all the District Soviets, and
               subsequently those of the Provinces, are from now on and until the Constituent
               Assembly meets, full-powered bodies of State authority in their localities. All
               landlords’ titles to the land are cancelled by the second All-Russian Congress of
               Soviets. A decree regarding the land has already been issued by the present
               Provisional Workers’ and Peasants’ Government. On the basis of the above decree all
               lands hitherto belonging to landlords now pass entirely and wholly into the hands of
               the Soviets of Peasants’ Deputies. The <hi rend="italic">Volost</hi> (a group of
               several villages forms a <hi rend="italic">Volost</hi>) Land Committees are
               immediately to take over all land from the landlords, and to keep a strict account
               over it, watching that order be maintained, and that the whole estate be well
               guarded, seeing that from now on all private estates become public property and must
               therefore be protected by the people themselves.</p>
            <p>All orders given by the <hi rend="italic">Volost</hi> Land Committees, adopted with
               the assent of the District Soviets of Peasants’ Deputies, in fulfilment of the
               decrees issued by the revolutionary power, are absolutely legal and are to be
               forthwith and irrefutably brought into execution.</p>
            <p>The Workers’ and Peasants’ Government appointed by the second All-Russian Congress of
               Soviets has received the name of the Council of People’s Commissars.</p>
            <p>The Council of People’s Commissars summons the Peasants to take the whole power into
               their hands in every locality.</p>
            <p>The workers will in every way absolutely and entirely support the peasants, arrange
               for them all that is required in connection with machines and tools, and in return
               they request the peasants to help with the transport of grain.</p>
            <closer><signed><hi rend="italic">President of the Council of People’s Commissars,</hi>
                  <name>V. ULIANOV (LENIN).</name></signed>
               <placeName>Petrograd,</placeName><date when="1917-11-18">November 18th,
               1917.</date></closer>
         </div>
         <div type="numeric" n="2">
            <p>The full-powered Congress of Peasants’ Soviets met about a week later, and continued
               for several weeks. Its history is merely an expanded version of the history of the
               “Extraordinary Conference.” At first the great majority of the delegates were hostile
               to the Soviet Government, and supported the reactionary wing. Several days later the
               assembly was supporting the moderates with Tchernov. And several days after that the
               vast majority of the Congress were voting for the faction of Maria Spiridonova, and
               sending their representatives into the <hi rend="italic">Tsay-ee-kah</hi> at Smolny….
               The Right Wing then walked out of the Congress and called a Congress of its own,
               which went on, dwindling from day to day, until it finally dissolved….</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
