<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="full">Ten days that shook the World/Appendices</title>
            <title type="full">APPENDIX TO CHAPTER VII</title>
            <author cert="high">John Reed</author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Texte encodé dans le cadre du devoir GIT de l'ENC</resp>
               <name>Julien Fenech</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
            <publisher ref="contributor">Internet Archive</publisher>
            <pubPlace>New York, New York, United States of America</pubPlace>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ten Days That Shook the World by John Reed</title>
               <distributor
                  facs="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Ten_Days_That_Shook_the_World/Appendices"/>
               <biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="420">pp.325-420</biblScope>
            </bibl>
            <biblStruct>
               <monogr>
                  <imprint>
                     <publisher>Boni and Liveright</publisher>
                  </imprint>
               </monogr>
            </biblStruct>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <creation>
            <date when="1919">1919</date>
         </creation>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textDesc n="novel">
            <channel mode="w">printed</channel>
            <constitution type="single"/>
            <derivation type="original"/>
            <domain type="art"/>
            <factuality type="mixed"/>
            <interaction type="none"/>
            <preparedness type="prepared"/>
            <purpose type="entertain" degree="high"/>
            <purpose type="inform" degree="high"/>
         </textDesc>
         <settingDesc>
            <setting>
               <name>Russia</name>
               <time>October 1917</time>
            </setting>
         </settingDesc>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head>APPENDIX TO CHAPTER VII</head>
         <div type="numeric" n="1">
            <head>TWO DECREES</head>
            <div>
               <head>On the Press</head>
               <p>In the serious decisive hour of the Revolution and the days immediately following
                  it, the Provisional Revolutionary Committee is compelled to adopt a series of
                  measures against the counter-revolutionary press of all shades.</p>
               <p>Immediately on all sides there are cries that the new Socialist authority is in
                  this violating the essential principles of its own programme by an attempt against
                  the freedom of the press.</p>
               <p>The Workers’ and Peasants’ Government calls the attention of the population to the
                  fact that in our country, behind this liberal shield, is hidden the opportunity
                  for the wealthier classes to seize the lion’s share of the whole press, and by
                  this means to poison the popular mind and bring confusion into the consciousness
                  of the masses.</p>
               <p>Every one knows that the bourgeois press is one of the most powerful weapons of
                  the bourgeoisie. Especially in this critical moment, when the new authority of the
                  workers and peasants is in process of consolidation, it is impossible to leave it
                  in the hands of the enemy, at a time when it is not less dangerous than bombs and
                  machine-guns. This is why temporary and extraordinary measures have been adopted
                  for the purpose of stopping the flow of filth and calumny in which the yellow and
                  green press would be glad to drown the young victory of the people.</p>
               <p>As soon as the new order is consolidated, all administrative measures against the
                  press will be suspended; full liberty will be given it within the limits of
                  responsibility before the law, in accordance with the broadest and most
                  progressive regulations….</p>
               <p>Bearing in mind, however, the fact that any restrictions of the freedom of the
                  press, even in critical moments, are admissible only within the bounds of
                  necessity, the Council of People’s Commissars decrees as follows: </p>
               <list rend="numbered">
                  <item n="1">The following classes of newspapers shall be subject to closure: (a)
                     Those inciting to open resistance or disobedience to the Workers’ and Peasants’
                     Government; (b) Those creating confusion by obviously and deliberately
                     perverting the news; (c) Those inciting to acts of a criminal character
                     punishable by the laws. </item>
                  <item n="2">The temporary or permanent closing of any organ of the press shall be
                     carried out only by virtue of a resolution of the Council of People’s
                     Commissars. </item>
                  <item n="3">The present decree is of a temporary nature, and will be revoked by a
                     special ukaz when normal conditions of public life are re-established.</item>
               </list>
               <p> President of the Council of People’s Commissars,</p>
               <p><name>VLADIMIR ULIANOV (LENIN).</name></p>
               <p>* * * *</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>On Workers’ Militia</head>
               <list rend="numbered">
                  <item n="1">All Soviets of Workers’ and Soldiers’ Deputies shall form a Workers’
                     Militia. </item>
                  <item n="2">This Workers’ Militia shall be entirely at the orders of the Soviets
                     of Workers’ and Soldiers’ Deputies.</item>
                  <item n="3">Military and civil authorities must render every assistance in arming
                     the workers and in supplying them with technical equipment, even to the extent
                     of requisitioning arms belonging to the War Department of the Government. </item>
                  <item n="4">This decree shall be promulgated by telegraph. Petrograd, November 10,
                     1917.</item>
               </list>
               <p>People’s Commissar of the Interior</p>
               <p><name>A. I. RYKOV. </name></p>
               <p>This decree encouraged the formation of companies of Red Guards all over Russia,
                  which became the most valuable arm of the Soviet Government in the ensuing civil
                  war.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="numeric" n="2">
            <head>THE STRIKE FUND </head>
            <p>The fund for the striking Government employees and bank clerks was subscribed by
               banks and business houses of Petrograd and other cities, and also by foreign
               corporations doing business in Russia. All who consented to strike against the
               Bolsheviki were paid full wages, and in some cases their pay was increased. It was
               the realisation of the strike fund contributors that the Bolsheviki were firmly in
               power, followed by their refusal to pay strike benefits, which finally broke the
               strike.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
